《斯巴达克斯：血与沙》
《兄弟烙印》
漂亮！
Yes!
斯巴达克斯
Spartacus,
再次成为胜者！
Victor again!
Solonius门下尚且残存有人 这真是奇迹啊！
It's a marvel good solonius has any men left!
每次竞技终极勇士 必是这个色雷斯人不成？
Must the thracian appear in every primus?
堂堂Batiatus家族 难道没有另一角斗士
Does the house of not deem another gladiator
可以技惊四座吗？
Worthy of spectacle?
除却此人 他们也没什么能人斗士了
They have no one else of note.
不久之后 Crixus亦将重铸辉煌
Crixus will return to glory, presently.
但愿如您所说啊
As you say.
不二人选啊
A welcome addition.
这个色雷斯人真令人心生厌倦 总是他一人取胜
I grow tried of this thracian and his victories.
有件重要之事或许可以稍减枯燥
Perhaps something of note to erase the tedium.
我将在明天的拍卖会上购进一批新的奴隶
I purchase a fresh batch of slaves at auction tomorrow,
并将他们训练成角斗士
To be trained as gladiators.
若您能赏光受入仪式
We would be honored if you would
我们将倍感荣耀
Grace us at the unveiling.
你准备买什么样的野人啊？
What sort of beasts shall you procure?
最剽悍的
Only the most ferocious,
一切随您心意
To be displayed for your pleasure.
下一场拍卖即将开始
Our next auction is about to begin.
我们财运亨通啊！
Fortune favors us!
挑点好的 我们的钱足够了
A fine selection, enough coin to take our pick.
您的对手来了
Your competitor approaches.
Solonius 真让我喜不自胜啊！
Solonius, my heart brims with joy!
我早就盼着您来了
I had hoped to see you here,
多买些新人 好让斯巴达克斯屠戮啊！
Buying new men for spartacus to slaughter!
Batiatus 你现在也侍财倨傲 鸡犬升天了啊
Batiatus, now purse-proud and so potent with charm.
世事变幻无常啊 对吧？
How quickly fortuna shifts her blessings. Huh?
我的爱侄Ovidius可没机会知晓实情了啊
A fact that beloved ovidius was unexpectedly made aware.
言之有理
You speak truth.
他被谋杀实属悲剧
His murder was a deep tragedy.
的确如此
Indeed.
没人会知道暴行的始作俑者了 是吧？
One can never know who is plotting violence, can one?
或许他们还会再犯下罪行呢
Or when they may commit the act.
慷慨的卡普亚市民们
Good citizens of capua.
拍卖会开始了 主人
The auction begins, dominus.
进入正题吧
To business, then.
这条血肉身躯绝对是上乘绝品…
Behold the finest offering of flesh and bone…
这个高卢人Segovax要价比较高
The gaul segovax will demand expense.
或许您还可以考虑这对日耳曼兄弟 Duro和Agron
And perhaps the german brothers, duro and agron.
还有其他人选吗？
The others?
均不值一提
Of little worth.
首先向您推荐 这位享有堂堂声誉的
Let us begin with a celtic gaul
高卢凯尔特人！
Of imposing virtues!
为您推荐！
I give you!
请看Segovax
Segovax, an imposing gaul, is pulled forward.
赤身就是战袍！
Skin, his armor!
双手就是兵器！
Hands, his steel!
谁欲领取此人？
Who would claim such a man?!
敬请出价！
Bid!
五迪纳币！
Five denarii!
尊贵的Vibius出价五迪纳币！
Five denari from good vibius!
十迪纳币！
Ten denarii!
十二！
Twelve!
十五！
Fifteen!
二十！
Twenty!
二十五迪纳币！
Twenty-five denarii!
我都懒得出价了
I grow tired of bidding.
一百迪纳币！！
A hundred denarii!!
一百？
A hundred?
我全买下了
For the entire lot.
成交！
Sold!
归Batiatus了！
To batiatus!
卡普亚的救世主！
Savior of capua!
主人 无意冒犯
With respect dominus,
您开出的价位 已远远超出了他们实际所值
Your coin far exceeds their value.
去他娘的价值！
Fuck value!
没有什么能比 看到这个狗杂碎
None can be placed on seeing
拜倒在我脚下 更让人愉悦的了
That cock eater's pride ground beneath my heel.
Solonius 考虑一下这些贱女吧！
Solonius, consider the whores!
把女人派往竞技场角斗
Perhaps you will have better fortune
没准就能时来运转啊！
Fighting women in the arena!
我没能满足你吗 主人？
Have I not pleased you, domina?
你那阳物依旧萎靡啊？
Does your cock stand dry?
我怕难以力撑挺入
I fear you have not quaked.
抱歉
Apologies.
我的伤口尚未完全愈合
My wounds have yet to fully heal.
你会完全恢复 重振雄风的嘛
Well you will recover and all will be as it was.
抱歉打扰
Forgive me.
主人从市场回来了
Dominus returns from the market.
出去吧
Get out.
你要我怎么做？
What would you have me do?
如果我拒绝了 主人她一定会心生疑虑
If I refuse, domina will grow suspicious.
我知道
I know.
我尽力表现出自己很虚弱
I perform as weakly as I can,
希望她能对我失去性致
Hoping she will lose interest.
我没有生你的气
I am not angry with you.
只是…
It's only…
只是很痛苦
I find it difficult
看到你和主人共享欢愉 而我们却没有这样的机会
That you and domina share what we have not.
会有那么一阵不快
For some time.
我的心为你专属
You alone occupy my thoughts.
你死定了！
You're gonna die!
我会杀了你
I'm gonna kill you.
你死定了
You're dead.
我要杀了你！
I'm gonna kill you!
你死定了 你死定了
You're dead, you're dead,
这下你们死定了 全部死定了
Now you're dead, you're all dead.
你脚下踩着的是什么？
What is beneath your feet?
沙地？
Sand?
该死的白痴
Fucking idiot.
斯巴达克斯
Spartacus.
神圣的土地 Doctore！
Sacred ground, doctore!
被血泪所浸染的战场！
Watered with tears of blood!
你们的眼泪
Your tears.
你们的鲜血
Your blood.
你们这些可悲的生命
Your pathetic lives,
经过锻炼而有了价值…
Forged into something of worth…
赌那说话的蠢蛋5迪纳币
Five denarii on the fool who spoke.
听从 学习
Listen. Learn.
或许 可以活下来
And perhaps, live.
成为角斗士
As gladiators.
现在 留心你们的主人！
Now, attend your master!
你们将被保佑！
You have been blessed!
你们的每一个人
Each and every one of you,
将在这里找到自我
To find yourselves here,
在Quintus Lentulus的训练场里
At the ludus of quintus lentulus
这里全共和国最优秀的角斗士！
Purveyor of the finest in all of the republic!
在以后的艰苦岁月里 证明你们自己
Prove yourselves, in the hard days to follow.
证明你们不只是个普通的奴隶
Prove yourselves more than a common slave.
不只是个简单的男人 败 即亡
More than a man. Fail, and die.
你丈夫说话像我爸
Your husband speaks as my father would
在议院时一样
Before the senate.
真是个好演说家
He's quite the orator.
拥有阿波罗的口才啊
The tongue of apollo.
成功 就能骄傲地立于我的战神们之中！
Succeed, and stand proud among my titans!
Batiatus，batiatus，batiatus！
Batiatus, batiatus, batiatus!
角斗士从不畏惧死亡
A gladiator does not fear death.
他拥抱它
He embraces it.
爱抚着它
Caresses it.
干它…
Fucks it…
你觉得新人们怎么样？
What make you of the new men?
他们可真壮观啊！
They are spectacles!
我发现我已深深沉迷于这种
I find myself growing quite fond of this
肮脏的角斗士交易之中了
Sordid business of gladiators.
也许你该考虑
Perhaps you should consider purchasing
给你自己也买一个了
One of your own.
买角斗士？
A gladiator?
不可能的
I could never.
我可以吗？
Could I?
挑一个新人 就是你的了
Choose a recruit, and he is yours,
当然 象征性地给一点
For a nominal fee, of course.
毕竟需要金钱开销
Such funds to cover the expense
他的生活和训练费用
Of his upkeep and his training.
竞技场里的每一次胜利
Every victory in the arena,
都是对女主人的致敬
Is an honor to his domina.
该选哪一个好呢？！
Who should I choose?!
请让我来帮您挑选一个吧？
May I offer a suggestion to aid your dilemma?
Doctore啊！
Doctore!
我们尊敬的客人希望 检视一下新人们的品质
Our honored guest wishes to access the recruits' virtues.
把衣服脱了！
Remove your cloths!
我想要改一下我的赌注了
I wish to alter my bet.
全压在那个阳物最大的人身上
Everything on the one with the horse cock.
左边的那个…
The one on the left…
Segovax 高卢人
Segovax, gaul.
他肯定受到了生殖之神的眷顾
He has truly been blessed by the god priapus.
选得不错啊！
A fine specimen!
我们一定要庆祝庆祝！
We must celebrate!
取些酒来
See to the wine.
谁可以娶到这么好的妻子啊？
Has a man ever had such a wife?
而且还深爱着她的丈夫
She but loves her husband,
希望他步步高升
And would see him elevated.
属于我自己的角斗士
A gladiator of my own,
和Crixus来自同一个地方！
Mined from the same lands as crixus!
我的朋友们知道了 肯定会为之尖叫
The envy of my friends shall spread like locusts,
羡慕死我的
Their hearts devoured.
谁会这么嫉妒你啊？
Who would you torture so?
希望 可别是我认识的人
No one of my acquaintance, I hope.
这可不一定
Doubtful.
Caecila Aemilia啊…
Caecila, aemilia…
Licinia啊
Licinia.
Licinia 是Marcus Crassus的表亲吗？
Licinia, cousin to marcus crassus?
全罗马城最富有的人
The wealthiest man in rome,
至少他是这么讲的
According to him, at least.
Licinia 非常享受这些比赛
Licinia, in particular enjoys the games.
更喜欢竞技场中如野兽般的勇士
More so the beasts who do battle in them.
你该私下里发个邀请函
You must make invitation for private
把你的Segovax介绍给她们认识
Introduction to your man segovax.
让她们来这边玩
Here at the villa.
呃 这些都是正统的罗马女人
Uh, these are proper roman women.
她们只和同地位的家族成员来往
They only mingle with families of equal standing.
哦 也许这样就足够了
Oh, perhaps it's for the best.
看着你勇士的肉体
Seeing your man in the flesh
只会让她们更加嫉妒
Would only inflame their envy.
我会去安排的
I will arrange it
我还会来帮你做做头发
And I shall even help you with your hair.
一定要让你在这样高层的聚会中 看起来很适宜
We must make you look suitable for such elevated company.
在太阳下烘烤的废物们
Shit baking in the sun.
就好像昨天 我们还和他们一样呢
Seems only yesterday we were of a similar position.
真是时过境迁啊
Much has changed.
你已成为该死的卡普亚战神了
You became the fucking champion of capua.
你的传奇将万古流芳
Your myth to echo for a thousand years.
- 而我… - 成为了我的挚友
- And I… - Became a good friend.
Varro 骰子喊你呢！
The die call your name!
Varro这就来
And varro answers.
你还要赌？
You continue to gamble.
花点钱也好打发时间啊
A few coins to pass the time.
你他妈的急什么 角斗士们
You fucking wait until gladiators
都还没填饱肚子呢
Have filled their bellies.
Crixus啊
Crixus.
让他们吃吧
Let them eat.
他们必须忍受痛苦和折磨 才能成为角斗士
They must embrace pain and suffering to become gladiators.
就该如此做
This is how it is done.
轮不到你管
Not by you.
让他们吃吧
Let them eat.
斯巴达克斯 多宽厚仁慈啊
Spartacus… the kind and gentle one.
不要误解我的意思 Crixus
Do not mistake me, crixus.
我是懒得理这些人
I give no shit about these men.
你不再是卡普亚的战神了
But you are no longer the champion of capua.
这里你不再独大
You do not take lead here.
只是手下而已
You follow.
手下就要一直紧随你左右
The man who follows is forever at your back.
这才称得上战神
Something to consider champion.
该死的高卢人
Fucking gauls.
十分感激
Much gratitude.
死也要做个饱死鬼吧
Men should not die with empty stomachs.
Rhaskos啊
Rhaskos.
嗯 已到月末了 是吧？
Um, end of the month already, is it?
根据你读不懂日历算的
According to the calendar you cannot read.
你赢的钱总计三个半迪纳币
Your winnings amount to three and a half denarii.
是要钱呢 还是要爽一下？
Preserve coin, or indulge yourself?
我什么时候要钱不要女人了？
When do I ever take coin over gash?
我期望她屁股最好擦干净了
I expect her ass to be returned free of blood.
Ashur 你错过我的房间了
Ashur, you pass my cell by mistake.
我的钱呢？
Where is my coin?
错是你自己种下的
The mistake is yours.
不想打的话 你就没资格享受金钱
You do not fight, you are entitled to neither coin
或者女人
Nor cunt.
迟早会传到主人耳朵里的
The dominus shall hear about this.
哦 名单正是他写的
Oh his very hand set the names.
或许下个月 你就会发现自己
Perhaps next month you should find yourself
又会回到他们之中
Again among them,
前提是你的伤先好
Should your wounds ever heal.
Varro 等一下
Varro, a moment.
你几次胜利赢了不少钱了
your victories amass much coin.
我是一如既往地 把钱交给你妻子呢？
Shall I see it transferred to your wife as usual?
还是…
Or…
你想花点零头
Would you prefer a small portion
来缓解一下压力呢？
Applied towards more pressing concerns?
那矮子就是他妈的卡普亚战神吗？
That tiny man is the fucking champion of capua?
该死的罗马人把他的传奇
Fucking romans swell his legend
鼓吹成自己的优势
To their advantage.
我们轻易就能打败他 Agron
We could easily best the man, agron.
斯巴达克斯打败了死亡之影
Spartacus defeated theokoles.
他胜利的荣耀闪烁苍穹
And the skies wept to honor of his victory.
你们两个的挑战
The two of you would present challenge
根本不值一提
Equal to piss and shit.
你认为我说的很有趣吗？
You find my words amusing?
你说的 不
Your words, no.
说这些的那傻帽
The stupid fuck that speaks them,
才真他妈搞笑
Very fucking amusing.
斯巴达克斯是很好的例子
Spartacus is a man to be held as an example.
这个奴隶点燃了竞技场
The slave ignites the arena.
有一天 这把火会让他挣破枷锁
One day the flames shall set him free.
我曾经见证过同样的事
I've witnessed such a thing.
人们欢呼怒嚎 要求角斗士
The roar of the crowd, demanding a gladiator
因其在竞技场的表现 而获取自由
Be granted freedom for his showing in the arena.
你连和他称兄道弟
You haven't even earned the mark
他妈都不配
Of the fucking brotherhood
还叫嚣会自由
And you cluck about freedom.
Segovax说得没错
Segovax is right.
斯巴达克斯给我们指明了道路
Spartacus shows us the way.
我要像他一样训练
I will train as he trains,
铭记每一次冲击与抵抗
Every thrust and counter committed to memory.
然后有一天…
And one day…
我也将成为竞技场的传奇
I too will become legend in the arena.
啊！
Raaa!
治好他的伤还要点时间
His wounds need yet more time.
还要多久？
How much longer?
两到四周吧
A fortnight or two.
可能六周
Perhaps three.
啊… 该死的神啊！
Uhh…Jupiter's cock!
药剂师没在 要是有那些草药的话
His recovery may be aided by certain herbs
他的伤会好得更快
Absent the apothecary.
主人 我已经很久没摸过我的剑了
Dominus, I've been without sword for too long.
让我继续训练吧
Let me resume training.
我要去看看 需要哪些药
I will see all on the list procured.
听医师的话
Heed medicus' warning.
你的剑很快就会回到手中的
Your sword will return to your hand soon enough.
曼陀罗草… 莨菪…
Mandragora… Henbane…
碱液… 曼陀罗花…
Lye… Thorn apple…
铁杉… 颠茄… 还要半打
Hemlock… Belladonna… Half a dozen more.
很大的订单啊 得花多少钱啊
Substantial lists, requiring substantial coin.
都给我拿最好的
Procure the highest quality.
药用得好 就能有好治疗效果
A justified expense, should remedy result.
希望上天看到他妈的这一切
May the gods see it fucking so.
已经很多天没有起色了
Too many days pass without progress.
Doctore被Theokoles砍伤的时候…
When doctore suffered wounds from theokoles…
也没见他们要求相同的治疗时间啊？
Did they require equal time in the healing?
相当的少
Considerably less.
或许只是徒劳罢了
There might be a blessing
白费功夫
Hidden among such a curse.
就拿Crixus的真实情况来说吧
Talk of crixus' true condition
显然也还是逃不过这关了
Surely has not escaped beyond these walls. Yet.
你的意思是？
Your meaning?
看看怎么能冠冕堂皇地
Inquiries for his purchase could be made
把他卖了
In a delicate fashion.
我此去市场可以达成两个目的
My visit to the market could serve dual purposes.
别想打歪主意
Remove the thought.
停止所有 有关卖掉Crixus的谈论
There'll be no talk of selling crixus.
主人 我只是为以后着想
I only fear for the future, dominus.
他永远生活在斯巴达克斯的阴影之下
One that does not see spartacus erased from it.
别他妈跟我绕圈子
Straighten your fucking tongue
说明白点
And speak plainly.
昨天 我亲眼目睹 Crixus对斯巴达克斯的仇恨
Yesterday I witnessed the hatred cultivates
已经到了无以复加的地步
Towards spartacus, grow beyond measure.
按他的火爆脾气来看
If in his mad passion
Crixus 会以身犯险…
Crixus, were to make attempt on his life…
孤身挑战斯巴达克斯
Solicit numbers from sextus, alone.
Crixus恢复延迟的流言 绝不能传开
Word of crixus' stunted recovery must not to spread.
我只希望能 好好挖掘他的现有价值
I wish only to discover his current value.
你会把Crixus卖了？
You would sell crixus?
我要想尽一切办法敛财
I would explore all avenues of reason.
如果您真要这样 钱财会源源不断的
Which has flown if you consider such a thing.
Crixus会重新战斗
Crixus will fight again.
但还会像以前一样所向披靡吗？
But will he ever be the man he was?
给他点时间治伤 Quintus
Give him time to heal, quintus.
他和常人无异 受伤了也会流血
He bleeds when pierced, as does any man.
观众可不这么认为
The crowds do not see a man.
他们把他当成神 我们亦如此尊待他
They see him a god, and we present him as such.
一旦神话破灭 他的价值也不复存在
Should that myth evaporate, so goes his worth.
那我们会在其他方面找到价值
Then we'll find worth in another role.
他的知识肯定可以给下面的人
Well surely his knowledge would aid instruction
一些指导的啊？
To the lower men?
你已经有了个Doctore
We already have a doctore.
在任何竞技场 他都是最出色的
The finest in any ludus.
那他可以和你并肩作战
He could work beside you, then.
Crixus要的不是钱
Crixus has no head for numbers.
沙场才是他的唯一目标
The sword is his only purpose.
他是这个家的一员 Quintus！
He's part of the family, quintus!
他就是个他妈的奴隶！
He is a fucking slave!
这家房子 这个家 都只是个交易 Lucretia
This house, this family, is a business, lucretia.
卖掉像Crixus这般的角斗士 确实很遗憾
As much regret results from selling a gladiator like crixus,
只要时机成熟 他们都他妈地会被卖掉
When the time arrives, and it fucking will for them all,
这是没办法的办法
It's a necessity that must be swallowed.
还没做最后的决定
No decision has yet to be made.
他也许还能证明自己能行
He may still prove himself fit.
多操心下Ilithyia和她的朋友们吧
Turn your mind towards and her friends.
赢得了她们的青睐 这个家族才会更加荣光
Win their favor, and see this family rise ever higher.
不错
Good.
但前冲的时候 你的盾掉下来了
But you lower your shield when you thrust.
这样会把你从肩部到脖子全部暴露出来
It leaves you open from shoulder to neck.
再来一次
Again.
Crixus啊
Crixus.
你来干嘛？
What are you doing?
Doctore无处不在
Doctore's gaze misses nothing.
不幸把危机变成了必然
A risk made necessary by unfortunate events.
你发生了什么事？
Has something happened to you?
我一直很安全
I am ever safe.
但主人…
But dominus…
他考虑 把你卖给别的主人
He considers selling you to another master.
你肯定搞错了
You're mistaken.
已经派Ashur去市场买草药…
Ashur has been sent to market for herb…
同时也是去询问Vibius对你有没有兴趣
And to question vibius on his interest towards you.
Vibius？Lanista那狗杂种！
Vibius? Lanista of shits and mongrels!
我在竞技场所赢得的荣耀
The glory I have earned this ludus,
他妈地竟然换来了这些！
This is my fucking reward!
Crixus 你必须向主人证明
Crixus, you must prove to dominus
你的时代还没有过去
That your time has not passed.
作为角斗士踏上战场
To step onto the sand as a gladiator
是奴隶无比期盼的最高荣耀
Is the highest position a slave can pray for.
证明你自己
Prove yourselves.
赢得兄弟之谊的标记
Earn the mark of the brotherhood.
你这一击还真重
You strike a solid blow.
还是对个没怎么训练的傻子
Against an ill-trained fool
他玷污了高卢人的名声
Who taints the name of gaul.
他也许是个傻子
He may be a fool.
但他能够训练
But he is one who is fit to train.
再来
Again.
你觉得我没痊愈吗？
You doubt that I am fully healed?
兄弟 我将会证明你的错误
Coz I will show you otherwise.
Doctore Crixus自称恢复了健康
Doctore, crixus offers a demonstration,
希望重回训练！
To the benefit of the recruits!
我该同意吗？
Shall I indulge?
他相信自己已准备好了
He believes himself ready.
我也一样
As do I.
Segovax 你的剑和盾给他
Segovax, your sword and shield.
列队！
Attend!
Crixus 看看谁才是战神！
Show then whose champion, crixus!
放马过来吧
Show me.
他进攻毫无章法
He attacks boldly
只求速战速决
To hasten victory.
与正常训练刚好相反
Counter to proper training.
失败不仅仅源自手中的剑
Defeat is delivered not only by the sword,
同样来自于观众
But also the crowd.
跌落神坛
Fall from their grace,
也许你再也得不回以前的荣耀了
And you may never rise to former glories.
真正的角斗士 要学会忍受
A true gladiator is taught to embrace
伤痛与磨难
Pain and suffering.
战斗 直到生命的最后一刻
To fight until life flees from his worthless body.
吸取他的教训
Learn from this man.
否则殊途同归
Or share his fate.
斯巴达克斯！
Spartacus!
回去训练
Return to training.
是 主人
Dominus.
Rhaskos Hamilcar 出列
Rhaskos, hamilcar.
带他去看医师
See him to the medicus.
不错的价格 善良的Vibius
A fine offer, good vibius.
我迫不及待地想要转达给我的主人
I shall hasten to present it to my master.
等一下 奴隶
A moment, slave.
你竟然背着Batiatus经常光顾市场？
You frequent the market absent batiatus?
我以他的名义来进行重要交易
I conduct important business on his behalf.
有关前卡普亚战神的吗？
Regarding the former champion of capua?
我不会谈论此类交易
I discuss no business of the like.
如果我是你的话 我会
I would, if found in your position.
Crixus只是名义上的战神而已
Crixus is champion in name only.
不过就是人为刀俎 他为鱼肉罢了
He is but limbs, dangling from a skewered trunk.
把他当给像Vibius这样讨人厌的人
Your master would be well served
你主人算盘打得不错啊
Pawning him off on a toad like vibius.
你替我主人的考虑已经收到
Your concern for my master is well received.
我不是为他考虑 而是为你
My concern is not for him, but about him.
你听到了吗？
Are your ears receptive?
我无权阻止一个自由人发表言论
I cannot stop a free man from speech.
Batiatus认为我冒犯了他
Were batiatus, were to seek reprisal for offenses
就向我报复
He believes I have made,
我希望事先能得到警告
I would wish warning in advance.
我就是个坏蛋
I am a villain.
但我不会为你作恶
But I'm not your villain.
找其他奴隶吧
Seek another slave.
忠诚如果没有适当的支持
Loyalty can become a crushing weight,
终会把人压扁
If not braced by proper support.
当你感觉到重压之时
When your back begins to break,
你会发现我宽广的臂膀在迎接着你
You'll find my shoulders broad and welcoming.
你的自不量力
You overreach.
造成了现在的恶果
And here is the result.
别把我说得跟个新人一样
Do not address me as you would a recruit.
那就别表现成那样
Then do not act like one.
从伟大的斯巴达克斯 送雨的使者
Words of import from the mighty spartacus,
嘴里说出的东西！
Bringer of rain!
屠灭死亡之影的勇士！
Slayer of theokoles!
如果是你独自和他作战
As if you stood against him on your own.
没有我的相助 你就一无所有了
Without my aid, you would have nothing.
就连你现在的痛苦生活也会失去
Not even your miserable life.
没错
True.
但我站在了这里
But here I stand.
你却倒在了那里
And there you sit.
你根本不明白怎么做战神
You know shit about being champion,
也不明白什么是真正的兄弟
Of being a true brother.
你只是在那儿自以为是
You are only playing at your own part.
但总有一天游戏会落幕
And one day the game will end.
我们都难逃一死
Death comes to us all.
再激怒我 你就死定了
Press me again, and you shall find yours.
感谢各位今晚
Gratitude for joining us this evening,
莅临Batiatus家族
At the house of batiatus.
我跟你们聊得真是投机
Indeed has spoken so very highly of you that,
感觉像是遇到了老友一样
I feels if I'm with old friends.
噢 这可真是失误
Oh, that's a disadvantage.
Ilithyia从没说过她与
Ilithyia neglected to mention she was acquainted
Batiatus的妻子相交甚好
With the wife of good batiatus.
我肯定有提过
I am sure I must have.
你不说还真没发现 她真够贱的
She is quite the bitch, if you have not noticed.
所以我们大家都喜欢她
Which is why we love her so.
我也越来越爱她了
I grow rather fond of her myself.
嗯 我得喝杯酒 润润舌尖
Mmm, I could use a cup of wine to wet the tongue.
您可以开怀大饮 喝到醉倒
You could be drowning, and gurgle the same.
噢！
Oh!
嗯 这是Sestian酒么？
Mmm. Is this sestian?
是费勒年葡萄酒
Falernian.
嗯 她真费心啊 是吧？
Mmm, she is trying hard, is she not?
那是因为我跟她说过 你们对我有多重要
Only because I have told her how important you are to me.
是的 我们都很友爱
Yes, we all love each other
喜欢在新月下狂欢
And have orgies under the new moon.
现在跟我们讲讲故事吧！
Now tell us stories!
对 跟我们讲讲这个可怕的地方！
Yes, tell us everything about this horrid place!
她是指下面的训练场
She means the ludus below.
这还用你解说吗？
Do I need an interpreter?
当然
Apparently.
安静 听她说！
Do be quiet, let her speak!
你怎么能活在这群野兽之中？
How do you live among such beasts?
我的丈夫驯服了他们
My husband sees them well tamed.
我觉得不完全吧
I pray not fully.
还保存了些本性
Some instinct remains.
所以他们可以在角斗场释放兽性
So that they may yet unleash their savagery in the arena.
我要是住这里 会抓狂的！
I would go insane here!
在这山顶上 还被一群野兽所包围
Surrounded by all these animals, high atop this mountain.
你就不想住到城里
Would you not prefer to live in the city,
和真正的人们呆在一起么？
Surrounded by real people?
我觉得这里很好
I find that we are perfectly located.
我只要走出阳台
I need only step out onto my balcony
所有的卡普亚人就会臣服于我的脚下
And all of capua kneels at my feet.
说得好
Well stated.
但你不闷吗？
But are you not bored?
在这上面 孤孤单单的？
Up here, all alone?
除了奴隶和野兽外 一无所有
Nothing but slaves and beasts,
甚至也没有孩子…
Not even children to occupy…
闷？
Boredom?
这么多好玩的事情 才不会呢！
Impossible with so many distractions!
我一直很忙
I stay quite occupied.
每天都有新的机会
Each day brings with it opportunity.
实际上 昨天就有6个新人
Yesterday, in fact, six new recruits
投入了训练
Began their training.
其中一个还是Ilithyia买下的 为她而战
One of whom fights under ilithyia's patronage.
Ilithyia你？
Ilithyia?
Claudius准许你这么做？
Claudius gave you approval?
他不知道
He does not know.
只要一点钱 我自己的补贴就够了
A few coins, parceled from my allowance.
他知道了会杀死你的！
He will kill you when he finds out!
那我就会杀掉第一个告密的人 Caecilia！
And I will kill the first who tells, caecilia!
嗯 你有个专属的角斗士！
Mmm, a gladiator of your own!
我们能看看吗？
May we see him?
当然 他现在还不是角斗士
Course, he's not yet a gladiator.
他必须通过最后测试
He must pass the final test
才能加入Batiatus的角斗士队伍
Before he earns the mark of batiatus.
噢 所以他现在只是个奴隶咯？
Oh. So he is only a slave, then?
噢 只是暂时的…
Oh, for the time being but…
我更想看看真正的角斗士
I would lay eyes upon a real gladiator.
是啊！
Yes!
战神！
A champion!
把斯巴达克斯带上来！
Bring spartacus up!
斯巴达克斯 噢 是啊！
Spartacus, oh yes!
必须的！
You must!
把战神带上来
Bring the champion.
让他为我们的狂欢助兴
Let us all revel in his psence.
非常感谢
Gratitude.
你在我训练时的相助
For your aid in my training today.
我很想听听你
I would be eager to hear any advice,
对我日后的建议
To further my cause.
对你？
Your cause?
怎样在竞技场上获得荣耀 和自由
Victories in the arena, and freedom.
抛弃自由的想法
Forsake any thoughts of freedom,
摒弃你曾有的这高墙之外的生活
And the life you once had beyond these walls.
接受命运…
Accept your fate…
或者是被曾经一切 一去不复返的恐惧击倒
Or be destroyed by specters of a past never to return.
斯巴达克斯 主人传唤
Spartacus, you are summoned.
嗯 他跟个战神一样屹立 时刻准备战斗
Mmm, he stands as mars, ready for war.
传言是真的吗？
Is there truth to the legends?
角斗士们和诸神血脉相连？
Gladiators share the blood of the gods?
最有可能的 应该是强大的Crixus
The mighty crixus, most certainly.
而今 有个男人！
Now there was a man!
真正被神明赐福！
Truly blessed by the gods!
他何时能重返竞技场？
When will we see him in the arena again?
很快
Soon.
你究竟是什么 斯巴达克斯？
What of you, spartacus?
是神灵赐予我们的使者吗？
Are you a blessing to us?
对某些人来说 是的
To some.
对其他人 却是诅咒
To others, a curse.
像他这般的双面人
A duality of his kind.
虽然是披戴荣光的角斗士
Admired as a gladiator.
却也是一名卑贱的奴隶
Yet despised as a slave.
他可远胜一名普通奴隶
He is much more than a common slave.
你能感知 他肉体散发出的力量…
You can feel it radiating from his flesh…
我曾听过一个传说
I have heard tale of a champion's blood
战神之血 蕴含着惊人的滋补能量
Possessing many restorative powers.
据说 在一杯酒中 掺入几滴冠军之血
A few drops in a glass of wine is said
能令一个男人 坚挺数日之久！
To make a man hard for days!
传说而已
Such are the legends.
我想亲身验证这传说 请问我可以吗？
Well I would test them for myself, if I could?
当然可以
Certainly.
我会派信使 送去一小瓶血液…
I'll send a messenger with a vial…
就现在吧
I would have it now.
我能获此荣耀吗？
May I have the honor?
当心 伤口别切太深
Take care not to cut too deeply.
传说刻是要一名死去角斗士的血液啊
The legend does call for the blood of a dead gladiator,
不是吗？
Does it not?
不过 我们无需挂心这等小事
But such details should not concern us.
斯巴达克斯 很快就要丧命…
Spartacus will die soon enough…
在观众的吼叫中死去
To the roar of the crowd.
我可不相信 他会命丧竞技场
I do not believe he will ever fall in the arena.
他是角斗士中的神
He is a god among men.
他无非是条色雷斯狗
He's nothing but a thracian dog.
他的叛变 令罗马蒙羞
His treachery dishonored rome.
是你的丈夫 令罗马蒙羞
It is your husband who bears the dishonor.
守卫！
Guards!
他抛弃手无寸铁的妇孺
He abandoned defenseless women and children.
陷他们于被强暴和杀戮的绝境
Left to be raped and murdered.
把他带下去！
Get him out of here!
真是出言不逊！
What a bold tongue!
抱歉
Apologies.
若他是我的奴隶 我定要将他钉在十字架上处死！
Were he my slave, I would have him crucified!
为什么？
For what?
就因为口吐真言么？
Speaking the truth?
我们都听过关于你丈夫的流言
We've all heard the rumors about your husband.
天色已晚 还有人等着我呢
The hour grows late, and I'm expected.
感谢你分享 如此趣味盎然的一夜
Gratitude for a most interesting evening.
希望这样的夜晚 能很快重现
One that begs a repeat soon.
抱歉
Apologies.
无须如此
None required.
你马上就会知道 身份显赫的女士
You will soon learn that women of note
是多么渴望
Have a rabid taste
看到朋友们尴尬窘迫的场面
For the embarrassment of their friends.
我可不希望 我的朋友被人如此欺辱
Well I would not see mine treated so.
在我离开前 我能和Segovax说几句话吗？
May I have words with segovax, before I take my leave?
我希望能为他往后的日子 带来好运气
I wish to bid my man good fortune in the days to follow.
哈哈！
Ahh!
哈 我的运气又回来了！
Ah, my fortune returns!
Varro啊
Varro.
我正赢着呢
I'm of a winning mind.
省省你那归劝的说辞吧
Save your words of caution.
我并非来劝说
I'm not here for words.
我是来赌博的
I'm here for dice.
你 来赌博？
You and dice?
我今晚情绪不佳
I am of a mood tonight.
心烦意乱
I would have distraction.
我可是带了钱来的
And coin.
那么 老规矩
The rules, then.
我如果需要提示 自然会问
Should I need instruction, I shall ask.
我们要单独呆一会儿
Leave us.
知道我是谁吗 奴隶？
Do you know who I am, slave?
抱歉
Apologies.
我不知道
I do not.
我是你的主人
I am your domina.
我付钱供你训练
My coin pays for your training.
提供水
Water.
和食物
Food.
还有你呼吸的每一口空气
The very air you breathe.
若能幸存 烙上印记
Survive to receive the mark,
你将成为我的角斗士
And you will become my gladiator.
我培养的战神
My champion.
主人
Domina.
取悦于我
Please me,
你将获得丰厚的奖赏
And the rewards will be substantial.
美酒…
Wine…
女人…
Women…
甚至是 自由
Even freedom, perhaps.
你很渴望吧？
You desire such a thing?
渴望自由？
Freedom?
是的 主人
Yes, domina.
我也有所渴望
There is something I desire.
若能满足我的渴望
See it attended to,
你自可获得自由…
And your freedom will be secured…
你们真不该召唤斯巴达克斯！
Should never have been summoned!
我没得选择
I had little choice.
该把他和Ilithyia分开
Ilithyia, and the man should be kept separate.
放他们在一起 简直是自找麻烦
Throwing them together invites calamity.
有风险 但也有赚头
The risk bore fruit.
Lincinia 表明会再次拜访
Lincinia, intimates another visit.
她对斯巴达克斯有意思？
Spartacus her purpose?
毋庸置疑
Undoubtedly.
那我们得做些调整
Then we shall accommodate.
她的表亲Crassus掌控着这片天
Her cousin good crassus owns the fucking heavens,
即使他当前 并未获得
Even if he is not currently favored by
议院盟友的拥戴
His fellows in the senate.
你的努力 会让我们站得更高
Your efforts raise us ever higher.
你那边如何？
And how do yours fare?
有人对Crixus报价吗？
Have you received offers for crixus?
我明天将会见Vibius
I meet vibius tomorrow.
怎么是Vibius？
Vibius?
他的训练场在大马士革呢！
His ludus is in damascus!
Crixus在小地方才能更好的过活
Crixus will fare better in the smaller venues,
除非他痊愈
Until he is healed.
呃 那就明天 如何？
Well, tomorrow, then?
他的荣耀已渐渐远去
His glory fades.
但我不会让这荣耀 在我的掌中熄灭
I would not have it extinguish beneath our roof.
大马士革吗？
Damascus?
主人明天要去面谈
Dominus meets with tomorrow.
我还从未去过大马士革呢
I've never seen damascus.
你觉得我会喜欢那里吗？
Do you think I'll like it?
你不能去
You cannot go.
此事已成定局
The decision is made.
连女主人都不再信任我了
Even domina doubts me.
我从她的眼中就能看出
I see it in her eyes.
那就想办法说服她
Then convince her otherwise.
我的话无足轻重
My words carry no weight.
我从不对主人进言
I do not speak of words.
你想让我劝服主人？
You would have me do this?
我希望你留下来
I would have you stay.
这是你输给我的钱
The coin you lost to me.
赢了就是你的
Which makes it yours.
你真是个傻瓜
You are a fool.
你以前也曾赌博
You have thrown dice before.
数年前 我已金盆洗手
I turned from such things years ago.
为了我的妻子
For my wife.
跟我相比 你真是个好男人
You are a better man than I.
别忘了你为何沦陷于此 Varro
Do not forget why you are here, varro.
- 拿开你的手 - 你让家人蒙羞
- Remove your hand. - You dishonor your family.
你给你老婆丢脸
You dishonor your own wife.
我老婆是个荡妇！
My wife is a whore!
她怀上了别人的孩子
She carries another man's child.
怎么会这样？
How did this come to be?
一个朋友 集市上认识的
A friend, from the marketplace.
她声称是被逼 但是…
She claims he forced his way onto her, but…
你将过错归咎于她？
And you find fault with her?
她没有反抗
She did not fight.
若不是你为了偿债而离家
Had you not left to pay your debts,
她又何至于糟蹋自己
She would not have had to.
她还活着 Varro
She lives, varro.
她还活着
She lives.
你仍可以拥她入怀
You may yet hold her in your arms.
一个宽厚的男人 该懂得珍惜
A thought a decent man would cherish.
我丈夫正在集市上 商谈你的价钱
My husband is at market on business concerning you.
他相信你的荣誉 已渐渐远去
He believes your day may have passed.
你呢？
And you?
我祈祷他是错误的
I pray he is mistaken.
你所祈祷的神明呢？
And your gods?
他们有回应你的祷告吗？
Do they answer your prayers?
他们沉默无言
They're silent.
那就让我们力破苍天…
Then let us crack open the heavens…
获得他们的关注…
And gain their attention…
让那些对我荣耀不再的疑云…
Remove any doubt…
烟消云散…
That my day has passed…
啊！
Ah!
喔！
Oh!
她看起来… 很高兴
She seemed… Pleased.
Naevia啊
Naevia.
你已尽心尽力
You did what you had to.
按我的吩咐行事
What I asked of you.
主人已经在集市
Dominus is already at market.
和Vibius商谈呢
Speaking with vibius.
天无绝人之路
There is nothing that cannot be undone.
你是个好男人 Crixus
You are a good man, crixus.
神明不会忍心让你受此磨难
The gods will not see you treated so.
如今 他们青睐斯巴达克斯
They now favor spartacus.
对我不屑一顾
They give no shit for me.
原谅我 战神…
Forgive me, champion…
为了救一个你所憎恶的人…
You'd kill a fellow gaul…
你宁可杀死一个高卢人？
To save a man you hate?
我救的不是斯巴达克斯
I do not save spartacus.
我救的是 一位铭刻着相同印记的兄弟
I saved a brother who shares the mark.
你赚到了一个光荣的死法…
You have earned a glorious death…
你将死在角斗士的手中
And will die at the hands of a gladiator.
我他妈才离开这里一小会儿
I leave these walls for a fucking moment
就有一个新兵蛋子企图杀死斯巴达克斯
And a recruit tries to kill spartacus,
Ilithyia自己的操蛋手下？！
Ilithyia's own fucking man?!
若不是有Crixus 说不定他真成功了呢
And he would have succeeded, if it weren't for crixus.
他的荣耀还未逝去
His days not passed.
操！
Oh fuck!
告诉Vibius
Send note to vibius.
Crixus不卖了
Crixus is no longer for sale.
噢 恐怕协议已经敲定了
Oh, I feared termsere already agreed upon.
去他妈的协议！
Well fuck the terms!
他有意见 叫他来和我的老二理论
Should he have issue, he can reason to my cock.
哈 蛇蝎毒妇来了 还挺人模人样的
Ahh, the snake arrives, walking as if human.
希望我没有错过测试吧？
I pray I have not missed the test?
由于某些极为不幸的事情 测试已经推迟
Delayed, due to most unfortunate events.
斯巴达克斯 卡普亚战神
Spartacus, the champion of capua,
在洗澡的时候 被人出其不意地偷袭了
Was attacked unawares in the baths.
偷袭？
Attacked?
是你的新人 Segovax干的好事
By your recruit, segovax.
真是不幸
How unfortunate.
为你的奴隶不幸 是的
For your man, yes.
他得接受惩罚 必须的
He had to be punished, of course.
斯巴达克斯还活着
Spartacus yet lives.
是的
Yet.
你的人 不肯坦白原因
Your man would not speak as to his reason,
即便是阉了他老二 也不说
Even when parted from his cock.
昨晚你召见他的时候
He gave you no sign of cause
他并未露出任何马脚 是吗？
When you met with him last night did he?
没有 这真令人费解
No. It is a mystery.
我会重新夺回我的战神之位
I will regain my position, champion.
我欢迎你的挑战
I welcome the attempt.